William Lescaze Papers
William Lescaze Papers
- Individual commissions
  - 440 Magnolia Petroleum exposition building, Dallas, Texas
    - Drawings, 1 rendering (Oversize 3)
  - 443 CBS Studio #7, NYC, tracings and blueprints; includes rough sketch, preliminary floor layouts and elevations, floor plan and details for new studio radio station WABC, and details for lettering on studio floor, air conditioning and electrical, control desk speaker bafle, etc.. (Box 28)
  - 444 CBS elevator study, NYC (Box 29)
  - 450 Churston Development hotel, Devon, England, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - 451 Churston Development hotel, second batch houses
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 454 Churston Development hotel, third batch houses (Box 30)
  - 455 Churston Development hotel, fourth batch houses, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - 501 CBS-WBBM Studios, Chicago
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Photographs (Oversize 5)
  - 507 Frederick V. Field apartment, NYC (Box 30)
  - 509 Frederick S. Dunn house, Woodbridge, CT
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 31)
    - Photographs, 1 photograph (Oversize 2)
  - 512 John Gustavson house, Harvey Cedars, NJ (Box 31)
  - 514 Frederick V. Field house addition, Hartford, CT, 2 folders (Box 31)
    rough sketches, tracings for Schemes 1-4, plans and elevations, electrical layout, blueprint for bedroom, survey on linen
  - 515 CBS Hollywood Studios
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous, Photographs, drawings, renderings, elevations, photographs of models, more (Oversize 5)
    - "First drawings", 1 rendering (Oversize 17)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 516 J. Walter Thompson offices, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 photographs, 1 rendering (Oversize 2)
  - 517 Alfred Loomis house, Tuxedo Park, NY
    - Miscellaneous, several dozen photographs of interior and exterior; few nagatives; drawing of exterior; sketch of lighting fixture for bathroom; blueprint; detail sketches of lamp, desk, clock; clipping from magazine of diagram of house (Box 32)
    - Photographs, 4 photographs (Oversize 8)
  - 518 Time, Inc. offices, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 photographs, 1 rendering (Oversize 2)
  - 519 Bernard Rogers house, Rochester, NY (Box 32)
  - 520 W. H. Fain [Williams] house (Box 32)
  - 523 Kimble Glass office building, Vineland, NJ
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
    - Photographs, 4 photographs (Oversize 8)
  - 531 CBS San Francisco Studios (Box 32)
  - 532 Frederick V. Nash country house, Minneapolis, MN
    - Miscellaneous, photographs of Nash property (1936), exterior of house in progress near completion (1937) (Box 32)
    - Drawings, 1 rendering (Oversize 1)
  - 542 Howard Markel country house, Redding, CT (Box 32)
  - 545 Mrs. Mali playroom, NYC (Box 32)
  - 548 Kimble Glass superintendent's offices, Vineland, NJ
    - Miscellaneous (Box 32)
    - Photographs, 12 photographs (Oversize 8)
  - 549-570 CBS Studios, San Francisco and NYC
    - Miscellaneous, including photographs (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33)
  - 582 Aviation Building, World's Fair, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33)
    - Photograph (Oversize 8)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 584 Libby-Owen-Ford Building, World's Fair, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 33)
    - Photograph, 1 photograph of model (Oversize 8)
  - 586 Garage at Queensborough Bridge, NYC (Box 33)
  - 588 Garret A. Hobart III house, Tuxedo Park, NY
    - Miscellaneous, sketches, tracings, blueprints, memorabilia, photographs and negatives; 3 folders (Box 33)
      Rough sketches (27 items) - site, layout, furniture, etc.
      Numbered tracings (approximately 60 items) - plans, survey, elevations, plot plans, longitudinal sections, door schedule, kitchen layout, furniture layouts for all rooms, planting and paving plan, mechanicals for all floors, and details for shelving, windows, mirrors, lighting fixtures, bathrooms, skylight, fireplace, studio, railings, closets, etc.
      Blueprints (2 items)
      Memorabilia (3 items)
      Photographs and negatives of interior, exterior, and construction
    - Miscellaneous, 1 plan, 1 photograph (Oversize 17)
  - 597 Swiss Pavilion, World's Fair, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
    - Photographs, 1 photograph (Oversize 8)
  - 598 Goucher College competition, Baltimore (Box 34)
  - 600 CBS-WCAU auditorium alteration, Philadelphia, PA (Box 34)
  - 602 Lescaze House, 211 East 48th, NYC
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Photographs, 2 items (Oversize 2)
    - Photo panels, 3 items (Oversize 13)
    - Drawings, 1 rendering (Oversize 17)
  - 604 Frederick S. Dunn cottage, Woodbridge, CT
    - Miscellaneous (Box 34)
    - Photographs, 4 items (Oversize 9)
  - 606 Stacy May cottage, Martha's Vineyard, MA (Box 34)
  - 614B Benjamin J. Buttenwieser alteration, Bedford, NY (Box 34)
  - 617A Cherry Lawn School alteration, Darien CT
  - 617B Cherry Lawn School boy's dormitory
  - 619 Longfellow Building, Washington, DC
    - Miscellaneous, including photographs, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 36)
    - Photographs, 2 items (Oversize 9)
    - Photo panels, 2 items (Oversize 13)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 622 Harold Spivacke house, Washington, DC (Box 36)
  - 623 Metropolitan Museum of Art exhibition, NYC (Box 36)
  - 628 Edward A. Norman house, 124 East 70th, NYC
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous,s including photographs, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Photographs, 2 folders (Oversize 1)
    - Blueprints (Tube 2)
      Gift of Abigail Norman, 2020.
  - 630 Mrs. George Crawford guest house, Greenwich, CT, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - 634 Garret A. Hobart III alterations, Paterson, NJ (Box 37)
  - 639 Apartment house lobby alterations, Washington, DC (Box 37)
  - 643 Chelsea houses, NYC
    See also 749 Elliot Houses alterations.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
    - Drawing, 1 site plan (Oversize 2)
  - 643A Mrs. Joseph Barnes alterations, NYC
  - 648 Maurice Stone bedroom, NYC (Box 37)
  - 658 Frederick V. Field guest house, New Hartford, CT, photographs; 12 items (Box 37)
  - 673 Benjamin J. Buttenwieser child's bedroom, NYC (Box 37)
  - 680 Woods End defense housing, Roselle, NJ
    - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs, 2 items (Oversize 9)
  - 684 WLW Studios, Cincinnati, OH, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - 686 Dorie-Miller East Harlem Housing Project, NYC (Box 37)
  - 688 Pass & Seymour lighting fixture designs, Syracuse, NY (Box 37)
  - 692 Monsanto Chemical Company designs in plastic, NYC (Box 37)
  - 694 The Kawneer Company consulting, Miles, MI (Box 37)
  - 695 Architectural Forum design for filling station, NYC (Box 37)
  - 700 Spelman Prentice farmhouse alterations, Wheelock, VT (Box 37)
  - 704 J. Walter Thompson office layout, NYC (Box 37)
  - 706 CBS Theater #4, West 53rd St, NYC, sketches and drawings, including balcony and auditorium plans, structural and lettering details, framing, flagpole, room layout, etc.; includes items from Columbia Broadcasting Company (control room details), Chapman Metal Products (Kal work), Harold Ryan Inc., Air Conditioning, Pan American Iron Works, Inc. (details of pipe railings), and C.E. Halback and Co. (mixer console panels)
  - 713 Emerson Radio Cabinet design, NYC (Box 37)
  - 717 HOPE Windows, Inc., Jamestown NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
    - Research report, bound, clippings, blueprints, plans, etc. (Oversize 16)
  - 719 Pittsburg Plate Glass commercial, Pittsburgh, PA (Box 38)
  - 723 Cherry Lawn School, Darien, CT
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 725 Parking terminal, Boston
  - 731 WOR building sign, NYC, 4 renderings (Oversize 12)
  - 738 Johnson & Johnson research building, New Brunswick, NJ
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 740 City for children planning study, East Harlem (Box 38)
  - 749 Elliot Houses alterations
    See also 643 Chelsea houses, NYC.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 751 CBS microphones, NYC, 2 folders (Box 38)
    See also 431 CBS microphones.
  - 759 Scarsdale Recreation Survey, Scarsdale, NY (Box 38)
  - 760 Crosset Health Center, Crosset, AR
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 761 Chicopee Sales Corporation offices, NYC (Box 39)
  - 763 City Athletic Club addition, NYC, 6 photographs (Oversize 9)
  - 767 (Dr. Frank) Calderone Theatre, Hempstead (Long Island), NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 771 William Brown Meloney alteration at Sutton Square, NYC, 1923; includes items from first WL commission; 2 folders (Box 39)
    See also 131 Simeon Ford House, 2 Sutton Square, NYC.
  - 777 Radio station, Reykjavik, Iceland
  - 779 CBS Mobile unit, NYC, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - 780 Alfred Loomis House, Easthampton, NY (Box 40)
  - 785 Elementary School Norwood, NJ (Box 40)
  - 786 City & Municipal Courts Building, NYC
    See also 1000 City and Municipal Courts Building, NYC.
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 787 Public School 14, Richmond (Staten Island) NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 789 Crown Central Petroleum Corporation filling station, Baltimore (Box 40)
  - 791 Jerome Crowley house, South Bend, IN
    - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs, 4 items (Oversize 9)
  - 800 NY Housing Trust prefab research, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
    - Drawings, 3 chalk (?) renderings (Oversize 9)
  - 801 Reliance Steel Corporation prefab houses, Pittsburgh, PA
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
    - Photographs, 1 negative (Oversize 9)
  - 810 Sherwin S. Levey house, Candlewood Lake, CT
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Photograph, 1 item (Oversize 9)
  - 813 Belmont Hill School additions, Belmont, MA
  - 831 UNIWALL research, second stage (Box 41)
  - 832 Frederick V. Field house alterations, NYC (Box 41)
  - 844 Sydenham Hospital addition, NYC (Box 41)
  - 849A Harbor Homes housing development, Port Washington (Long Island), NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 849B Spinney Hill Homes, Manhasset, NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
    - Photographs, 4 items (Oversize 9)
  - 862 Durisol, Inc., house, Aberdeen, MD (Box 42)
  - 873 Dune Deck Hotel (Box 42)
  - 874 Sydney Kaye house, Cornwall Bridge, CT
    - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs, 10 items (Oversize 9)
  - 896 J. Walter Thompson office for Ruth Waldo, NYC (Box 43)
  - 899 Webb & Knapp alterations, NYC
  - 900 State Building Code Commission (Box 43)
  - 917 Republic Steel penthouse, Cleveland, OH (Box 43)
  - 928 Sculptors Guild exhibition, NYC, 1952 (Box 43)
  - 930 Porcelain Enamel Institute research, 4 folders (Box 43)
  - 931 Webb & Knapp addition, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 937 India Exchange, Ltd. Calcutta (Box 44)
  - 941 Cinerama Theater alterations, NYC (Box 44)
  - 942 Sutton House apartments, NYC (Box 44)
  - 951 711 Third Avenue, NYC
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Photographs, 5 photographs, including 3 of mural by Hans Hyman (Oversize 9)
  - 962 Government of India tourist information office, 11 East 58th NYC, 2 photographs (Oversize 9)
  - 980 School of Industrial Art, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 985 Salamanca Housing Project, Salamanca, NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Drawings, 3 renderings (Oversize 12)
  - 1000 City and Municipal Courts Building, NYC, See also 786 City & Municipal Courts Building, NYC.
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Project files and photographs, 1 set of project files (plans, renderings, descriptions), 2 portfolios of photographs (Oversize 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1 rendering, 1 photograph, 2 folios of preliminary documents and blueprints (Oversize 12)
  - 1009 Manhattanville Houses, NYC
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1014 U.S. Mission to the U.N. office layouts, NYC (Box 46)
  - 1015 Plainview Jewish Community Center, Long Island NY (Box 46)
  - 1017 CBS, 18th floor lobby, NYC (Box 46)
  - 1025 Borg-Warner Building, Chicago
    - Miscellaneous (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Printed advertising piece (Oversize 12)
  - 1045 Dune Deck Hotel, Westhampton Beach, NY (Box 46)
  - 1050 2 Broadway Building, NYC (Box 46)
  - 1057 Swiss Embassy Chancellery Building, Washington, DC
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Drawings, 6 floor plans (Oversize 2)
  - 1064 111 Pine Street, San Francisco, brochure, 1 photograph of rendering (Oversize 10)
  - 1072 30 West Broadway, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1083 Jerome Crowley house alterations, South Bend, IN, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - 1086 Benjamin J. Buttenweiser apartment, 450 East 52nd St., NYC (Box 47)
  - 1092 Swiss Embassy interiors, Washington, DC (Box 47)
  - 1100 Manhasset housing project, Manhasset, NY
  - 1101 200 East 58th apartments, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1107 Mayfair Theatre, 47th St. & 7th Avenue, NYC (Box 47)
  - 1108 Brotherhood-In-Action House, 40th St. & 7th Avenue, NYC (Box 47)
  - 1116 250 Greenwich Avenue, NYC (Box 48)
  - 1120 Shore Club Towers, Detroit, MI (Box 48)
  - 1121 Churchill apartment house, Los Angeles, CA
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1125 245 Park Avenue, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs, 9 photographs of model (Oversize 10)
  - 1135 Lawrence Buttenweiser apartment, 5th Avenue & 89th St, NYC (Box 48)
  - 1136 Monterey Tower limited dividend housing, 180th St. & Monterey Avenue, Bronx (Box 48)
  - 1140 10 East 70th Street, NYC, possibly motel/apartment house
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Photographs, 4 photographs of model (Oversize 10)
  - 1160 Washington Street Market project, NYC
    - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs, 4 photographs of model (Oversize 10)
  - 1161 74 West 92nd apartments, NYC (Box 48)
  - 1183 Methodist Church Center, East 44th St, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1185 300 East 42nd Building, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Drawings, 2 renderings, 2 photographs of renderings (Oversize 10)
  - 1194 777 Third Avenue Building, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous, including photographs, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Project book, photographs, 3 photographs, bound project book with photographs, plans, descriptions, etc., and 1 small box slides (Oversize 11)
  - 1195 First National City Bank World's Fair exhibition building, NYC
    - Miscellaneous, includes site plan, floor plans, planting plan, interior elevations, sections, finish schedules, furniture plan, and details for windows, metalwork, teller's counter, exterior door/window, assorted signage (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1204 59th St. & Madison Avenue Office Building, NYC (Box 49)
  - 1222 Speed-Park garage study (Box 49)
  - 1224 Stern's Department Store alteration, NYC (Box 49)
  - 1225 Goldwater Memorial Hospital auditorium and chapels, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Project book, plans, renderings, descriptions, etc. (Oversize 10)
  - 1229 979 Third Avenue Rothschild showroom and offices, NYC
  - 1241 200 South Michigan Avenue, Chicago (Box 49)
  - 1242 110 East 59th, NYC
  - 1249 905 Third Avenue, Post Office Building, NYC
  - 1263 Stratford Tower apartments, NYC
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1265 345 Park Avenue/580 Lexington Avenue, NYC
  - 1271 Hotel converted to apartments, Detroit, MI
  - 1282 Downstate Medical Center Garage, Brooklyn
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1284 Chatham Plaza Center, Pittsburgh
    - Miscellaneous (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous, 1 photograph, 1 rendering (Oversize 10)
  - 1285 Washington Market commercial, warehouse and industrial buildings, NYC (Box 50)
    See also 1160 Washington Street Market project, NYC.
  - 1300 Junior High School #24, Richmond (Staten Island), NY
  - 1305 Post Office, Hicksville (Long Island), NY
  - 1306 1 New York Plaza (Box 50)
  - 1318 Metro North housing project, East Harlem
    - Miscellaneous (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1325 Creedmoor Hospital rehabilitation center, Queens, NY
    - Miscellaneous (Box 51)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1330 1 Oliver Plaza (Oliver Tyrone Building), Pittsburgh
    - Miscellaneous, includes garage level plans, office building plans, interior and exterior elevations, first floor plans with exit stairs, 13th floor machine room, ductwork, landscape drawings, grading study, restaurant study scheme, miscellaneous sketches, exterior perspective, 6th Ave. entrance, and details of lobby wall finish, luminous ceiling, parapet, etc. (Tube 1330-A)
    - Miscellaneous, includes garage level plans, plans and "core plans" for 1st through 38th floors, 13th floor mechanical, roof plan and sections, sections and details for stairs and truck bay, wall sections and details for roof and bulokhead wall, garage/entrance ramp section, and details for curtain wall, louvers, storefront, elevator, toilets, elevator lobby floor, and "moving stairs" (Tube 1330-B)
    - Miscellaneous, includes master list of plans with drawing numbers, site plan, plans for garage level (all three floors and ramp), plans and core plans for 1st through 38th floors, 13th floor mechanical room, exterior elevations (including stonework), and details for lobby, interior columns, stairs, "moving stairs", elevators, plaza, truck bay, curtain wall, storefront, ironwork and toilets (Tube 1330-C)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 photographs of model, 1 rendering (Oversize 10)
    - Scale model
  - 1360 110 East 59th Street, NYC
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 51)
    - Miscellaneous
  - 1363 NYSE site study, NYC (Box 51)
  - 1376 1 Oliver Plaza (Oliver Tyrone Building) revisions, Pittsburgh
  - 1388 Chase Manhattan Bank canopies, NYC (Box 51)
  - 1411 2 New York Plaza, Broad & South Sts, NYC (Box 51)
  - 1422 Garage roof, Albany, NY
  - 1477 1155 Raymond Avenue Building, Newark, NJ (Box 51)
  - 1452 1 New York Plaza alterations, NYC (Box 51)
  - Slides and photographic negatives (Box 52)
  - Slides and photographic negatives (Box 53)
  - Slides and photographic negatives (Box 54)
- Architectural career
  - Joblist (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 55)
  - Schools (Box 55)
- Biographical material
  - Sketches and chronologies (Box 55)
  - Coate, Robert "Profiles" The New Yorker, Dec. 12, 1936 (Box 55)
  - Resumes (Box 55)
  - Exhibitions (Box 55)
  - Lectures and radio broadcasts (Box 55)
  - Memberships registration and appointments (Box 55)
  - Published on or by Lescaze and his work (Box 55)
  - Works executed (Box 55)
- Correspondence
  - A - E (Box 55)
  - F - Z (Box 56)
  - Albers, Jose F (Box 56)
  - American Institution of Architects (Box 56)
  - Architectural Forum (Box 56)
  - Architectural League of New York (Box 56)
  - Architectural Press (Box 56)
  - Architectural Record (Box 57)
  - Architectural Review (Box 57)
  - Architecture and design (Box 57)
  - Architecture forms and functions (Box 57)
  - Ballardie, Thompson and Matthews (Box 57)
  - Beline, Arthur S (commissioner) (Box 57)
  - Binet, Jean (Box 57)
  - Board of Standards and Planning for the Living Theatre (Box 57)
  - Building Research Advisory Board (Box 57)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum (Box 57)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council (Box 57)
  - Clauss, Alfred (Box 57)
  - Columbia University (Box 57)
  - Connecticut Library Association (Box 57)
  - Cooper Union, Student Association of the Institute of Architects (Box 57)
  - Cummings, George Bain (Box 57)
  - Dumper, Henry A (Box 57)
  - Empire State Architect (Box 57)
  - Exhibitions, 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Design (Box 58)
  - Hecksher, August (Box 58)
  - High School of Music and Art, New York City (Box 58)
  - Howe, George (Box 58)
  - Le Corbusier (Box 58)
  - Lescaze, Mary (Mrs. William)
    - 1921-1938, 1940s, 1950s, 7 folders (Box 58)
    - NY, 1930s? (Box 58)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, by and about (Box 58)
  - Moser, Werner M (Box 58)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 58)
  - Museum of Modern Art (Box 58)
  - New Helvetic Society, 1948-1949 (Box 59)
  - New Republic (Box 59)
  - New York City Federation of Women's Clubs (Box 59)
  - New York State Building Code Commission (Box 59)
  - New York University (Box 59)
  - Norman, Dorothy (Mrs. Edward Dorman) (Box 59)
  - Pasmore, Victor, by and about (Box 59)
  - Pepper, Beverly (Mrs. William) (Box 59)
  - Philadelphia Savings and Fund Society (Box 59)
  - Plus (Box 59)
  - Progressive Education Association (Box 59)
  - Princeton University (Box 59)
  - G. P. Putnam & Sons and others, 1938-1956; regarding monograph by WL on being an architect; 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Radio Daily (Box 59)
  - Santacilia, Carlos Obregon (Box 59)
  - Savings Bank Journal (Box 59)
  - School of Industrial Art, New York City (Box 59)
  - Serrand, Gabriel (Box 59)
  - Shelter (Box 59)
  - Soulages, Pierre (Box 59)
  - Syracuse University (Box 59)
  - TASK (Box 59)
  - United States, Office of War Information (Box 59)
  - University of Florida (Box 59)
  - WNYC, Educational Institute of the Air (Box 59)
  - WQXR (Box 59)
  - Western Arts Association (Box 59)
  - Wells College (Box 59)
  - Wingert, Paul S. (Box 60)
  - Worcester Art Museum (Box 60)
  - Yale University Press (Box 60)
  - Unidentified (Box 60)
  - Letters to the editor, New York Times and others (Box 60)
- Drawings
  - Architectural
    - by George Howe of Mellor, Meigs & Howe (PSFS), 1923 (Box 60)
    - by George Howe? Mellor, Meigs & Howe, Stokowski, 1926 (Box 60)
    - by Howe & Lescaze for Arts & Decoration, Aug 1934 (Box 60)
    - by William Lescaze and others (Box 60)
  - Architectural/miscellaneous
    - by William Lescaze (Box 60)
    - by unidentified (Box 60)
  - Industrial design
    - Ashtray, cigarette cases, salt & pepper shaker (Box 60)
    - Furniture, not used (Box 60)
    - Furniture and miscellaneous (Box 60)
    - Lamp fixtures, Kootz (Box 61)
    - Radiators, 1938 (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Etching, "Lord Algernon" for Pierre Girard, undated (Box 61)
      Gift of Dwight Lanmon, 2013.
    - Etching, "With Best Wishes for a Happy New Year", undated (Box 61)
    - Sketches, undated; pencil; pen and ink (Box 61)
- Legal and financial
  - Analysis of costs to owners and architects, 1939-1940 (Box 61)
  - Mary Lescaze, 1956; 1961; passport and International Drivers License (Box 61)
  - Certificates (Box 61)
  - Contract with G. P. Putnam & Sons for How to be an architect, 4 Feb 1941 (Box 61)
  - Lease, Oct. 1, 1932 - Sept.30, 1933 (Box 61)
  - Military Service Record, Switzerland, 1914 (Box 61)
  - Naturalization papers, March 18, 1929 (Box 61)
  - Passport, driver's permits, 1937-1938; 1956,; 1961 (Box 61)
  - Transportation identification card, 1935 (Box 61)
  - Memorandum of facts in connection with auction sale of 21 Sutton Place, Dec. 15, 1924 (Box 61)
- Memorabilia
  - Certificates, awards, other documents, in portfolio (Oversize 7)
  - Christmas cards (Box 61)
  - Clippings, See Scrapbooks.
  - Clipping and notes from trip, 1962 (Box 61)
  - Photographs
    - Samuel A. Crozer Residence, Philadelphia, PA, by Howe, before 1929 (Box 61)
    - L. Hoden Residence, Bryn Mawr, PA, by G. Howe (Box 61)
    - Philadelphia Savings Fund Society, by Howe, circa 1923 (Box 61)
    - 2 Sutton Place, NY, 1923; 1928 (Box 61)
    - Architecture by WL? (Box 61)
    - Drawings from "renderings" scrapbook, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Artworks by WL (Box 61)
    - Industrial design photographs from scrapbook (Box 61)
    - Howe, George (Box 62)
    - Lescaze, Mary (Box 62)
    - Lescaze, William (Box 62)
    - Lescaze, William and others (Box 62)
    - Lescaze, William and Mary (in studio?), artwork and other individuals (Box 62)
    - McCormick, Walter (Box 62)
    - Sculptures by others (Box 62)